Okay, so when you actually get down to the pressure washing stage, and you have the machine on; it's making all the noise, you just take and get; you have to stay back from the wood.
If you get really close to the wood it's going to damage the wood.
You need to stay back like eight to twelve inches away from the wood.
You sweep it back and forth, and you have to make sure you cover all the wood.
If you don't cover all the wood you're going to have streaks in it when you take and refinish it.
And the pressure washer will take off most everything that needs to be taken off, and in fact, if the wood is very old it will make the wood furry.
That means it'll have fibers out of the wood.
So then you can just go back over the wood with an orbital sander, and just take the furriness off the wood, because you don't want the wood to be furry when you're finishing it.
Now you have your pressure washer on, and you're pressure washing the deck up here, and the boards, and you're taking off the dirt.
You have to make very sure that you don't skip over places and, or it'll make lines where you leave the dirt and debris on here.
You have to be very symmetrical or congruent to get across here to make sure that everything is just nice and clean, and there's no stripes in it, or you'll end up with stripes when you finish the deck.
Okay, so you've pressure washed your deck, you've got it all down and nice and clean.
In Arizona here, it will dry out in twenty-four hours, but you have to make sure that the redwood is nice and dry before you put any of your treatments on.
If you're in another climate where it's wet or very humid you might have to wait two to three days.
You don't want to apply the treatment if there is any moisture in your deck, because it will tend to bubble.